<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workshops on Group IV News</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/tags/workshops/</link><description>Recent content in Workshops on Group IV News</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/tags/workshops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Higgs @GGI 2026</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/higgsggi-2026/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/higgsggi-2026/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the workshop &amp;ldquo;Higgs @ GGI 2026&amp;rdquo;, which will take
place from 28 September to 23 October 2026
at the Galileo Galilei Institute for Theoretical Physics (GGI) in Florence,
Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop is broadly devoted to Higgs physics, and aims to promote close
interaction between theory and experiments,
focusing on precision measurements, theoretical interpretations, precise
calculations and the prospects for BSM Higgs sectors.
All of this will be discussed in light of current and future runs of the LHC,
and looking at the perspective for future colliders following the outline of
the update of the European Strategy for Particle Physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event also features a mini-school and a mini-conference during its first
week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information on the program, participation, registration, and deadlines
is available on the event webpage: &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.ggi.infn.it/showevent.pl?id=535" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://www.ggi.infn.it/showevent.pl?id=535&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We kindly invite interested researchers to apply and participate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best regards,&lt;br&gt;
The organizers of Higgs @ GGI 2026,&lt;br&gt;
Emanuele Bagnaschi, Maria Cepeda, Paolo Francavilla and Ramona Gröber&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>SIGRAV-2026</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/sigrav-2026/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/sigrav-2026/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="scuola-sigrav-2026--neutron-stars-modelling-and-detection"&gt;Scuola SIGRAV 2026 | Neutron Stars: Modelling and Detection
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vietri Sul Mare (SA), Italy, 16-20 February 2026.&lt;br&gt;
(website, &lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/event/49236/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/event/49236/&lt;/a&gt; ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline Febraury 6, 2026&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program of the School comprises the following four courses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modelling of Neutron Stars as Gravitational Wave Sources&lt;br&gt;
o Lecturer: B. Haskell (Milano Univ., IT)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gravitational Signal from Late Inspiral and Merger of Neutron Stars&lt;br&gt;
o Lecturer: T. Hinderer (Utrecht Univ., NL)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detection of Continuous Gravitational Waves&lt;br&gt;
o Lecturer: M.A. Papa (AEI, Hannover, DE)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multimessenger Astrophysics with Neutron Stars&lt;br&gt;
o Lecturer: G. Ghirlanda (INAF, Brera, IT).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The School is intended for PhD students and young post-docs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>UNIVERSUM VII</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/universum-2026-registration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/universum-2026-registration/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear all,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;following up on our Save-the-Date announcement: registration for the VII edition of the UniVersum meeting series is now open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UniVersum VII — Naples (6–8 May 2026)&lt;br&gt;
Venue: Centro Congressi, Università degli Studi di Napoli&lt;br&gt;
“Federico II”&lt;br&gt;
Via Partenope, 36 – 80121 Napoli&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venue page: &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.centrocongressi.unina.it/via-partenope/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://www.centrocongressi.unina.it/via-partenope/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Conference website: &lt;a class="link" href="http://universum.to.infn.it/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;http://universum.to.infn.it/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please register here:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a class="link" href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdI3SEt3-sWfKd7ceE2O1llEd_hEHFm2QTlGSrRkcPXTdlv0A/viewform?usp=sharing&amp;amp;ouid=109649807390177458" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdI3SEt3-sWfKd7ceE2O1llEd_hEHFm2QTlGSrRkcPXTdlv0A/viewform?usp=sharing&amp;ouid=109649807390177458&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The registration deadline is 3rd April 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contributed talks (abstract submission)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants are warmly invited to submit an abstract if they wish to give a contributed talk. Given the limited number of available
slots, depending on the number of submissions we may need to select among the requests. In that case, we will give priority to
early-career participants (PhD students and postdocs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Social dinner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also planning a social dinner the first day. You will be able to indicate your participation during the registration process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accommodation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants are kindly invited to arrange their own accommodation directly with their preferred providers (Naples offers many options
within walking distance of the venue).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please circulate this information among potentially interested colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best,&lt;br&gt;
The UniVersum Steering and Local Organizing Committees&lt;br&gt;
Marco Baldi (UNIBO)&lt;br&gt;
Stefano Camera (UNITO)&lt;br&gt;
Carmelita Carbone (INAF, IASF, MI)&lt;br&gt;
Michele Liguori (UNIPD)&lt;br&gt;
Filippo Bouche (SSM)&lt;br&gt;
Vincenzo Fabrizio Cardone (INAF – Osservatorio Astronomico di Roma)&lt;br&gt;
Mariafelicia De Laurentis (UNINA, INFN)&lt;br&gt;
Noemi Frusciante (UNINA, INFN)&lt;br&gt;
Ester Piedipalumbo (UNINA,INFN)&lt;br&gt;
Giuseppe Sarracino (INAF – Osservatorio Capodimonte Napoli)&lt;br&gt;
Crescenzo Tortora (INAF – Osservatorio Capodimonte Napoli)&lt;br&gt;
Daniele Vernieri (UNINA,INFN)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Estate Quantistica a Scalea</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/scalea-2026/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/scalea-2026/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Colleagues,&lt;br&gt;
we are pleased to announce the sixth edition of Estate Quantistica, which
will take place in Scalea (Italy) from June 22 to June 26, 2026, at the
Grand Hotel de Rose.&lt;br&gt;
Estate Quantistica is an international scientific school and
workshop devoted to recent developments in gravity, cosmology, and
mathematical physics. The event is conceived as an advanced training
opportunity, particularly aimed at graduate students, postdoctoral
researchers, and early-career scientists, while remaining open to all
researchers interested in these topics.&lt;br&gt;
The scientific program consists of mini-courses delivered by leading
experts, complemented by contributed talks and ample time for discussions.
The invited lecturers for the 2026 edition include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luca Amendola (Universität Heidelberg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guido Carlet (Université Bourgogne Europe)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roberto Longo (University of Rome &amp;ldquo;Tor Vergata&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viatcheslav Mukhanov (Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dmitri Vassilevich (Universidade Federal do ABC)
The school will be held in a particularly favourable setting, combining an
intensive scientific program with an environment well suited for informal
exchanges and collaboration among participants.&lt;br&gt;
Further information on the event, including the scientific program,
practical details, and registration procedures, can be found on the official
webpage:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a class="link" href="https://monge.u-bourgogne.fr/gdito/EQ2026/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://monge.u-bourgogne.fr/gdito/EQ2026/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would be grateful if you could circulate this announcement among
interested colleagues and students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With kind regards,&lt;br&gt;
the Organisers,&lt;br&gt;
Giuseppe Dito (Université Bourgogne Europe), Júlio C. Fabris (Universidade
Federal do Espírito Santo), Alexander Kamenshchik (Università di Bologna),
Oliver F. Piattella (Università degli Studi dell&amp;rsquo;Insubria), Ilya Shapiro
(Universidade Federal de Juiz de Fora), Dmitri Sorokin (INFN, Padova
Section), Alexander Vikman (FZU, Czech Academy of Sciences), Vincenzo
Vitagliano (Università di Genova)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pollica workshops</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/pollica-2026/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/pollica-2026/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are extremely pleased to announce that the Pollica Physics
Centre (&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.pollicaphysics.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://www.pollicaphysics.com&lt;/a&gt;) will host 3 workshops the coming
summer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="mesoscopic-physics-in-the-era-of-quantum-computing---may-24th--to-may-30th--2026"&gt;“Mesoscopic physics in the era of quantum computing” - May 24th to May 30th , 2026
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;organized by Leonid Glazman (Yale U.), Bernard van Heck
(Sapienza U.), Angela Kou (U. of Illinois Urbana-Champaign),
Julia Meyer (U. Grenoble Alpes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Website &lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/event/49735" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/event/49735&lt;/a&gt;, Application
form &lt;a class="link" href="https://forms.gle/iuAK5KJ5AXF2eecZ7" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://forms.gle/iuAK5KJ5AXF2eecZ7&lt;/a&gt; (application deadline Feb 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="beyond-wimps-theory-and-model-building-for-the-next-generation-of-dark-matter-searches---june-1st-to-june-12th--2026"&gt;“Beyond WIMPs: theory and model building for the next generation of dark matter searches” - June 1st to June 12th , 2026
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;organized by Gianfranco Bertone (Amsterdam U. GRAPPA), Dan
Hopper (Wisconsin-Madison U.), Gordan Krnjaic (Fermilab), Tim
Linden (Stockholm U.), Kathelin Schutz (McGill U.), Jessica
Turner (Durham U.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Website &lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/event/49733/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/event/49733/&lt;/a&gt;, Application
form &lt;a class="link" href="https://forms.gle/2w9y7NBKVY1pNJa69" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://forms.gle/2w9y7NBKVY1pNJa69&lt;/a&gt; (application deadline Feb 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="scattering-amplitudes-from-positive-geometries-to-analytic-structures---september-14th-to-september-25th-2026"&gt;“Scattering amplitudes: from positive geometries to analytic structures&amp;quot; - September 14th to September 25th 2026,
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;organized by Lara Bossinger (UNA of Mexico), James Drummond (U.
of Southampton), Livia Ferro (U. of Hertfordshire), Ö. Gürdoğan
(U. of Southampton), Tomasz Lukowski (U. of Hertfordshire),
Andrew McLeod (U. of Edinburgh)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Website &lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/event/49734/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/event/49734/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
Application form &lt;a class="link" href="https://forms.gle/KWY5pcjZ3jPmeCma9" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://forms.gle/KWY5pcjZ3jPmeCma9&lt;/a&gt; (application deadline Apr 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applications are now open for each of them. We kindly ask you to forward
this announcement to potentially interested scientists. You can find the
poster in attachment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to hosting an exciting summer of physics again at the Castle
of the Princes Capano!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind regards,&lt;br&gt;
The PPC Steering committee (Angelo, Chiara, Mario, Mauro, Pietro)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>TALENT Course 10 on Nuclear Theory for New Physics</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/talent-2026/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/talent-2026/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear colleagues and friends,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with the start of 2026 come exciting announcements, including
that of the new TALENT course 10: &amp;ldquo;Nuclear Theory for New
Physics&amp;rdquo;. It will take place at the ECT* (Trento, Italy) from
Monday July 13 to Friday July 31 2026 and is organised
by Vincenzo Cirigliano (INT), Heiko Hergert (FRIB), Emanuele
Mereghetti (LANL), Saori Pastore (Washington University in St.
Louis), Maria Piarulli (Washington University in St. Louis), and
André Walker-Loud (LBNL).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This TALENT school aims to establish a common ground for nuclear
theory students in different sub-communities interfacing in the
study of electroweak and BSM physics with nuclei: phenomenology
and Effective Field Theory, lattice QCD, and nuclear structure.
More information can be found here:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.ectstar.eu/talents/nuclear-theory-for-new-physics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://www.ectstar.eu/talents/nuclear-theory-for-new-physics/&lt;/a&gt;
The school is tailored for PhD students and young post-docs with
in-depth lectures given by world-leading expert in each field
followed by problem-solving sessions The registration has
already opened on the Indico website:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a class="link" href="https://indico.ectstar.eu/event/279/registrations/161/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://indico.ectstar.eu/event/279/registrations/161/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to this very interesting TALENT school on such a
beyond-standard topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincerely yours,&lt;br&gt;
The TALENT board&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Conference BEACH 2026</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/beach-2026/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/beach-2026/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is our pleasure to announce that the XVI International Conference on Beauty, Charm, Hyperons in Hadronic Interactions (BEACH2026) will be held in Florence (Italy) from June 8 to June 12, 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This edition, hosted in the center of historic and culturally rich city of Florence, continues the BEACH series, which began in Strasbourg in 1995. The series offers a biennial opportunity for theorists and experimentalists from the high-energy physics community to discuss all aspects of flavour physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The abstract submission is open and will close on February 28, 2026. Contributions can be accepted as oral communications or posters. Abstracts can be submitted through the conference website
&lt;a class="link" href="https://indico.cern.ch/event/1537617" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://indico.cern.ch/event/1537617&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where all practical information regarding registration and accommodation will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any questions, please contact the Local Organizing Committee at &lt;a class="link" href="mailto:beach2026@lists.fi.infn.it" &gt;beach2026@lists.fi.infn.it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to welcoming you in Florence!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the Local Organizing Committee,&lt;br&gt;
Giovanni Passaleva (LOC chair, INFN Firenze)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>TFI 2026 a Brescia, 25-27 maggio 2026</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/tfi-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/tfi-1/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we are happy to announce that the 9th meeting TFI: Theories of the Fundamental Interactions, organized by the networks GAST, GSS and ST&amp;amp;FI, will take place at the center Paolo VI in Brescia on 25-27 May 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program will include three review lectures on topics of current interest, as well as talks by young researchers and a poster session. Dionysios Anninos (King&amp;rsquo;s College, London) and Zohar Komargodski (Simons Center For Geometry and Physics, Stony Brook) have already agreed to participate as review lecturers. Speakers for the talks will be proposed by the Network Nodes and reviewed by the organizers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registration is open at the conference website &lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/event/48355/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/event/48355/&lt;/a&gt;, where you can also find additional details.&lt;br&gt;
For people staying directly at Paolo VI, it is suggested to book a room in advance (there is a free cancellation option).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in the previous editions, the conference will be a great opportunity to bring together senior and young researchers of the INFN networks, therefore we kindly ask you to circulate the email between all the members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who wish to present their work at the Poster Session are invited to send a message with a title and an abstract of their work to &lt;a class="link" href="mailto:tfi2026@lists.infn.it" &gt;tfi2026@lists.infn.it&lt;/a&gt; with the Object: Poster Presentation TFI 2026 by April 20th 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope to see all of you in Brescia!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organizing committee and the Scientific Advisory Board:&lt;br&gt;
Roberto Auzzi, Stefano Baiguera, Lihan Guo, Giuseppe Nardelli&lt;br&gt;
Davide Cassani, Marialuisa Frau, Marta Orselli, Domenico Seminara&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>3rd Workshop on Quantum Computing @ INF | Second bulleting</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/qcomp-3-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/qcomp-3-2/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cari Colleghi,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desideriamo ricordarvi che la scadenza per l’invio degli abstract per la
terza edizione del Workshop Quantum Computing @ INFN è fissata per il 12
dicembre 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il workshop si terrà presso la Sezione e Università di Milano-Bicocca dal 3
al 6 Febbraio 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3rd Workshop on Quantum Computing @ INFN&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/event/48148/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/event/48148/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il programma, in via di definizione, prevede contributi di rassegna a invito
e presentazioni delle attività in corso.&lt;br&gt;
Per queste ultime, è necessario sottomettere un breve abstract utilizzando
il link apposito entro il 12 Dicembre 2025.&lt;br&gt;
Link per inviare l’abstract: &lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/event/48148/abstracts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/event/48148/abstracts/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il workshop è previsto in presenza. È necessario registrarsi per
partecipare.&lt;br&gt;
Link per la
registrazione: &lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/event/48148/registrations/5422/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/event/48148/registrations/5422/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per qualsiasi chiarimento vi preghiamo di rivolgersi a&lt;br&gt;
Concezio Bozzi – &lt;a class="link" href="mailto:bozzi@fe.infn.it" &gt;bozzi@fe.infn.it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Andrea Giachero – &lt;a class="link" href="mailto:andrea.giachero@mib.infn.it" &gt;andrea.giachero@mib.infn.it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vi aspettiamo a Milano!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cordialmente,&lt;br&gt;
Concezio ed Andrea&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Giornata in onore di Giancarlo Rossi</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/rossi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/rossi/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear colleagues,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in order to commemorate Giancarlo Rossi and honour his personal and
scientific achievements we have organized a one-day Memorial Meeting to be
held on FRIDAY 9 JANUARY 2026 in AULA MAGNA GISMONDI at University of Roma
Tor Vergata. We would very much like to invite you to participate in the
event and forward the announcement to potentially interested colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please visit the website&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/event/49337/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/event/49337/overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
for further information. Registration is free and online attendance is
possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to seeing you at GCR Memorial Meeting,&lt;br&gt;
Best regards&lt;br&gt;
Guido, Massimo &amp;amp; Velia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>International Symposium on Particles, Strings, and Cosmology</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/pascos2026/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/pascos2026/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Colleagues,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PASCOS 2026, the 31st
International Symposium on Particles, Strings, and Cosmology,
will be held at the University of Sheffield (UK) from 22–26 June
2026.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference will highlight recent advances in particle
physics, astroparticle physics, string theory, and cosmology,
with a strong emphasis on the interplay between these fields.
The programme will feature invited plenary talks and parallel
sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference website is now live, and registration and
abstract submissions for contributed talks and posters are open:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://indico.global/event/14705/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://indico.global/event/14705/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invited Speakers include:&lt;br&gt;
Tessa Baker • Francesco Benini • Florian Beutler • Philippe Brax
• Marcela Carena Lopez • Miranda Cheng • Djuna Croon • Raffaele
Tito D’Agnolo (TBC) • Tamara Davis • Francesca Di Lodovico •
John Ellis • Suvendu Giri • Diksha Jain • Cristina Lazzeroni •
Julien Lesgourgues • David Mulryne • Sara Pasquetti • Hiranya
Peiris • Vivian Poulin • Diego Redigolo • Adam Riess • Andreas
Ringwald (TBC) • Sakura Schäfer-Nameki • Sally Shaw • Sebastian
Trojanowski • Cumrun Vafa (TBC) • Iacopo Vivarelli • Kazuya
Yonekura&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We warmly encourage participation from early-career researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For inquiries, please contact: &lt;a class="link" href="mailto:pascos2026@sheffield.ac.uk" &gt;pascos2026@sheffield.ac.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to welcoming you to Sheffield next June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With best regards,&lt;br&gt;
The PASCOS 2026 Organising Committee&lt;br&gt;
Eleonora Di Valentino • Adam Brown • Carsten van de Bruck •
Davide Costanzo • Ed Daw • Sam Dolan • Marco Fazzi • Steffen
Gielen • Dan Tovey • Elizabeth Winstanley&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Quantum Gravity and Cosmology 2026 (QGC2026)</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/qgc2926/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/qgc2926/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QUANTUM GRAVITY AND COSMOLOGY 2026 (QGC2026)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9-13 February 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sala Ulisse, Palazzo Poggi, Via Zamboni 31 - Bologna, Italy&lt;br&gt;
Registration for the workshop &amp;ldquo;Quantum Gravity and Cosmology 2026&amp;rdquo; is now
open!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Webpage: &lt;a class="link" href="https://inspirehep.net/conferences/3087270" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://inspirehep.net/conferences/3087270&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the workshop is to bring together the experts working on
different UV complete approaches to quantum gravity, from string theory to
various perturbative and non-perturbative approaches. Given the promising
opportunity to probe quantum gravity effects in the very early Universe with
future CMB and gravitational wave experiments, we expect the in-depth
discussions on predictions and self-consistency of low- energy effective
theories on top of cosmological backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting will be mainly focused on the following directions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-perturbative methods, in application to quantum gravity, such as
string theory, amplitudes bootstrap, functional renormalisation group,
loop quantum gravity, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quantum gravity effects in the early Universe: inflation, cosmological
correlators, non-gaussianities, gravitational waves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EFT of gravity in connection with cosmology and Black Holes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;other related topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NB: Due to strict limitations in venue capacity and funding availability,
the number of conference participants is limited. The organizers reserve the
right to confirm registration requests.&lt;br&gt;
Contact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tronconi, Alessandro (&lt;a class="link" href="mailto:Alessandro.Tronconi@bo.infn.it" &gt;Alessandro.Tronconi@bo.infn.it&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>DIS2026 - International Workshop on Deep Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects (second bulletin)</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/dis2026-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/dis2026-2/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Colleagues,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is our pleasure to announce the opening of registration and abstract
submission for the 33rd International Workshop on Deep Inelastic Scattering
and Related Topics (DIS2026), which will be held in Bologna (Italy) from 4
to 8 May 2026. General information about the workshop was provided in the
First Bulletin, issued last September. You can now find detailed information
on registration, student support, travel, and accommodation at
&lt;a class="link" href="https://dis2026.infn.it" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://dis2026.infn.it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deadline for abstract submission is 15 January at 23:59 CET. Abstracts
may be submitted for contributed talks (17+3 minutes) or shorter (8 minutes)
“flash” talks. Flash talks will replace the traditional poster session and
are designed to provide early-career scientists with an opportunity to share
brief research communications. Abstract acceptance will be notified by 15th
February 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early-bird registration fee is 650 € until 15 March 2026, and 800 EUR
thereafter. For early-career scientists (undergraduate and PhD students),
the fee is 450 € (600 € after 15 March). The fee includes the welcome
reception, all lunches, coffee and tea breaks, the social dinner, and an
excursion in the Bologna city centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We strongly recommend booking your accommodation well in advance to save
money and ensure that you find an option suitable to your needs. Please see
related recommendations on the conference website. We have been informed
that a major fair will take place in Bologna during the final days of the
conference, which may make last-minute hotel bookings more difficult and
more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in previous editions, the 2026 Guido Altarelli Award will be presented
during DIS2026. The nomination deadline passed last 20 November, and the
award ceremony will be held on 8 May 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we ask a small favor to help us promote DIS2026. Since September,
we have quietly distributed DIS2026 posters to major laboratories and
universities through various collaboration meetings. The poster, printed in
A3 format, remains very readable. We invite you to download a copy and print
it to help advertise the conference in your department or laboratory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking forward welcoming you in Bologna!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any questions, please contact the organizers at&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a class="link" href="mailto:dis2026-info@lists.bo.infn.it" &gt;dis2026-info@lists.bo.infn.it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the Local Organizing Committee,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pietro Antonioli&lt;br&gt;
DIS2026 Chair&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>UNIVERSUM VII – Naples - 6–8 May 2026</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/universum-7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/universum-7/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear all,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we are pleased to announce that the VII edition of the UniVersum meeting
series will be held in &lt;em&gt;Naples&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Date: 6–8 May 2026&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Location: Centro Congressi, Università degli Studi di Napoli &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Federico II&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;
Via Partenope, 36 – 80121 Napoli
(&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.centrocongressi.unina.it/via-partenope/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://www.centrocongressi.unina.it/via-partenope/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;About the Meeting:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UniVersum is a series of cosmology meetings designed to bring together, on a
regular basis, members of the Italian cosmology community. These gatherings
aim not only to share scientific research and activities but also to
strengthen collaborations, discuss pressing scientific topics, and address
strategic choices for the community as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Venue:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seventh edition of UniVersum will be held in Naples, one of Italy&amp;rsquo;s most
vibrant and historic cities, famous for its cultural heritage, stunning
seaside views, and lively atmosphere.
The conference will take place at the Centro Congressi of the University of
Naples Federico II, a modern, fully equipped facility housed in a historic
university building right on the scenic Via Partenope waterfront, overlooking
the Gulf of Naples. The venue is within easy walking distance of major
landmarks, restaurants, and a wide range of accommodation options.
View the location on Google Maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accommodation:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naples offers many lodging options within walking distance, including hotels,
B&amp;amp;Bs, hostels, and Airbnbs. Participants are kindly invited to arrange their
own accommodation directly with their preferred providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will soon circulate a more detailed email with information on the
registration process, a call for abstracts, and a preliminary structure of the
meeting. This information will also be made available on the conference
website (&lt;a class="link" href="http://universum.to.infn.it/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;http://universum.to.infn.it/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please circulate the news among potentially interested colleagues and
&lt;em&gt;Save The Date!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UniVersum Steering and Local Organizing Committees&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marco Baldi (UNIBO)&lt;br&gt;
Stefano Camera (UNITO)&lt;br&gt;
Carmelita Carbone (INAF, IASF, MI)&lt;br&gt;
Michele Liguori (UNIPA)&lt;br&gt;
Filippo Bouche (SSM)&lt;br&gt;
Vincenzo Fabrizio Cardone (INAF – Osservatorio Astronomico di Roma)&lt;br&gt;
Mariafelicia De Laurentis (UNINA)&lt;br&gt;
Noemi Frusciante (UNINA)&lt;br&gt;
Ester Piedipalumbo (UNINA)&lt;br&gt;
Giuseppe Sarracino (INAF – Osservatorio Capodimonte Napoli)&lt;br&gt;
Crescenzo Tortora (INAF – Osservatorio Capodimonte Napoli)&lt;br&gt;
Daniele Vernieri (UNINA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>GGI International School 2026 on Frontiers in Nuclear and Hadronic Physics</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/fbhp-26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/fbhp-26/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Colleagues,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we would like to inform you that the registration to the International
Doctorate School &amp;ldquo;Frontiers in Nuclear and Hadronic Physics 2026&amp;rdquo; (FNHP2026)
is now open. The school will take place at the Galileo Galilei Institute
(GGI) in Florence, from February 16 to February 28, 2026. The school is
primarily addressed to Ph.D. students in Theoretical Nuclear and Hadronic
Physics. Participation of post-doc fellows and experimentalist is also
encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2026 edition will be devoted to the study of high-energy collisions from
proton-proton to nucleus-nucleus and it will provide a pedagogical
introduction to the basic concepts and tools needed for carrying out cutting
edge research in hot QCD matter, high-energy QCD, Quark-Gluon Plasma probes
and properties, relativistic hydrodynamics, particle production, QCD phase
diagram at finite temperature and density. The topics will be of main
interest for students and young post-docs working on hot QCD matter,
relativistic heavy-ion collisions, quark matter in astrophysics, hadronic
physics, and more generally on nuclear and particle physics. The lectures
will emphasize the intimate connections among these fields, giving much
attention to the interpretation of experimental data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L. Apolinario(LIP Lisbon): Jet Physics in ultra-relativistic collisions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N. Brambilla (Tech. Univ. of Munich): Non-Relativistic EFT and Lattice QCD
for Heavy Flavor Dynamics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G. Giacalone (CERN, Geneva): Nuclear Structure studies through
ultra-relativistic collisions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S. Schlichting (Bielefeld Univ.): Hydrodynamics and Kinetic Theory:
Attractors and Thermalization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. Vuorinen (Helsinki Univ.): Dense matter equation-of-state from colliders
to neutron stars&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will admit about 50 students.&lt;br&gt;
Accomodation in double rooms will be provided to a cost of about 40 Euro per
night (including breakfast). Lunches during the week-days will be offered
on site, free of charge, to all participants.
Financial support for accommodation expenses may be provided, upon request,
to a selected number of participants (about 35).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students from non-EU institutes/universities are supposed to provide a
&lt;a class="link" href="GGI-FNHP2026-letter.pdf" &gt;recommendation letter&lt;/a&gt;, to be sent to the School contact persons
(&lt;a class="link" href="mailto:andrea.beraudo@unito.it" &gt;andrea.beraudo@unito.it&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="link" href="mailto:greco@lns.infn.it" &gt;greco@lns.infn.it&lt;/a&gt;).
The deadline for application is December 18th, 2025. Acceptance will be
communicated by January 9th, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information and the application form can be found on the
website &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.ggi.infn.it/showevent.pl?id=552" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://www.ggi.infn.it/showevent.pl?id=552&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please circulate this information to colleagues and collaborators that might
be interested in the initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to welcoming your students,&lt;br&gt;
The organizers&lt;br&gt;
Alessandro Bacchetta (Pavia U.), Andrea Beraudo (INFN, Torino), Ignazio
Bombaci (Pisa U.), Angela Bonaccorso (INFN, Pisa) , Maria Colonna
(INFN-LNS), Vincenzo Greco (Catania U.), Elena Santopinto (INFN, Genova),
Luigi Coraggio (Campania U., Caserta), Enrico Vigezzi (INFN, Milano)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Special Challenges in Quantum Chromodynamics</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/sc-26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/sc-26/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Colleague,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are organizing a two-half-day workshop on advanced topics in perturbative
QCD, inspired by the scientific legacy of Stefano Catani.&lt;br&gt;
The event will take place on January 8 and 9, 2026, at the Galileo Galilei
Institute in Arcetri, Florence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year&amp;rsquo;s edition will focus on Sudakov resummation. We plan to critically
compare different resummation approaches, calculations in direct and conjugate
spaces, in Soft Collinear Effective Theory (SCET) and direct QCD, parton showers
and automated resummation techniques. We will also discuss the impact of
resummation on the description of heavy-quark fragmentation and shape variables
in e+e- annihilation, and its relevance for the accurate determination of the
strong coupling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confirmed invited speakers include Ugo Aglietti, Thomas Becher,
Matteo Cacciari, Stefan Kluth, Frank Krauss, Giovanni Ridolfi and
Giulia Zanderighi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further details and registration are available on the workshop webpage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/e/SC26" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/e/SC26&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The schedule will include ample time for discussions to encourage active
participation from all attendees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to seeing you in Florence next January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best regards,&lt;br&gt;
Roberto Bonciani, Leandro Cieri, Daniel de Florian, Prasanna Dhani, Giancarlo
Ferrera, Massimiliano Grazzini, German Rodrigo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>workshop in ricordo di G. Altarelli</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/altarelli-2025/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/altarelli-2025/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Care colleghe e cari colleghi,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a dieci anni dalla scomparsa di Guido Altarelli, abbiamo organizzato presso
l&amp;rsquo;Università Roma Tre, dove Guido ha lavorato per molti anni, una giornata
che intende ricordarne la figura ed il profondo impatto scientifico. Guido
Altarelli è stato una delle personalità più influenti della fisica teorica
italiana e internazionale, ed il suo lavoro ha contribuito in modo decisivo
alla nostra comprensione della fisica delle alte energie.
La giornata prevede interventi di ricercatori e colleghi che hanno condiviso
con lui parte del percorso scientifico.
L’iniziativa è aperta a studenti, ricercatori, docenti e a tutti coloro che
desiderano approfondire, condividere e ricordare l’eredità scientifica di
Guido Altarelli.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&amp;rsquo;evento si terrà il 2 dicembre 2025, dalle 14:30 alle 19:00 presso
l&amp;rsquo;Università di Roma Tre, Sala Conferenze di Ingegneria - Via Vito Volterra
62, Roma.
Pagina web: &lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/event/48870/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/event/48870/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Call for Abstracts &amp; Registration Open: AI_INFN Hackathon, Pavia (Nov 2025)</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/ai-hackathongalileo-2025/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/ai-hackathongalileo-2025/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear all,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;please be invited to the Second Advanced Hackathon on Machine Learning
organized by the AI_INFN CSN5 Initiative for dedicated to INFN employees,
associated members and students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event will be held in Pavia, at the Almo Collegio Borromeo, from
November 24th to November 27th, 2025. Attendance is free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agenda, still partially evolving, is available at
&lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/event/47736/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/event/47736/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registrations will open from Wednesday October 2nd at 9.00 am to Monday
October 13 at 11.59 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that if we receive a number of applications exceeding the
available seats, participants will be selected based on criteria including
the order of registration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The topics presented with theoretical lectures and practical hands-on
sessions include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Physics Informed Neural Networks applied to dosimetry in Medical
Physics;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quantum Machine Learning with QUBO;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compression pipelines for Gravitational Waves deployed in hardware with
FPGAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explainable GNN architecture with a mixture-of-experts orchestrator with
ATLAS Open Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The afternoons of Tuesday the 25th and Wednesday the 26th will be entirely
dedicated to guided work on these topics using the INFN Cloud infrastructure
at CNAF, ReCaS Bari and INFN Milano Bicocca.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first time, the Advanced Hackathon will feature research talks
selected through an open abstract submission process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contributions from both participants and other researchers are welcome, with
the goal of fostering a strong network of Machine Learning experts in
nuclear, subnuclear, and applied physics research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the attachment for further details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can reach the organizers for questions and comments at:
&lt;a class="link" href="mailto:ml-infn-hackathons@lists.infn.it" &gt;ml-infn-hackathons@lists.infn.it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Francesca Lizzi&lt;br&gt;
Lucio Anderlini&lt;br&gt;
Ian Postuma&lt;br&gt;
Francesca Brero&lt;br&gt;
Rosa Petrini&lt;br&gt;
Luca Clissa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>XXI Avogadro Meeting on Strings, Supergravity and Gauge Theories</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/avogadro-2025/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/avogadro-2025/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Colleagues,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that the &lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/e/XXIAvogadro" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;XXI Avogadro Meeting&lt;/a&gt; on Strings, Supergravity and Gauge Theories will take place in Catania (Italy), on December 17–19, 2025. The meeting will be held fully in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program will include five extended lectures with discussions, one gong-show session, one poster session. Young researchers are especially encouraged to apply for the gong-show and poster sessions. The deadline for registration is November 30, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lecture program will feature:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scale separation in string theory&lt;br&gt;
Speakers: Fien Apers (IFT, Madrid), Vincent van Hemelryck (Uppsala U.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent progress in 2d gauge theories&lt;br&gt;
Speakers: Diego Delmastro (UCLA), Giovanni Galati (ULB)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regge trajectories and light-ray operators&lt;br&gt;
Speakers: Alessandro Georgoudis (QMUL), Jeremy Mann (King&amp;rsquo;s College, London)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supersymmetric gauge theory methods for gravitational waves&lt;br&gt;
Speakers: Cristoforo Iossa (Geneva U.), Giulia Isabella (UCLA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SYK-like models and holography in lower dimensions&lt;br&gt;
Speakers: Ohad Mamroud (SISSA, Trieste), Jacopo Papalini (Gent U.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registration is already open, and we strongly recommend booking flights and accommodation early, as Catania is a popular destination also during the Christmas period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note also that a number of scholarships to support participation of early-career researchers will be available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in previous editions, we can only cover the costs of the social dinner for a limited number of participants. These will be decided based on the order of registration and are contingent on attendance to the meeting for all three days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further information and the application form are available at: &lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/e/XXIAvogadro" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/e/XXIAvogadro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also attach the official poster, and kindly ask you to print and display it at your institution. Please feel free to forward this announcement to anyone who might be interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carlo Heissenberg&lt;br&gt;
Michelangelo Preti&lt;br&gt;
Nicole Righi&lt;br&gt;
Matteo Sacchi&lt;br&gt;
Marco Scalisi&lt;br&gt;
Bernardo Zan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>DIS2026 - International Workshop on Deep Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects - 4-8 May 2026, Bologna</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/dis2026-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/dis2026-1/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Colleagues,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is our great honour to announce that the 33rd International Workshop on
Deep Inelastic Scattering and Related Topics (DIS2026) will be held in
Bologna (Italy) from 4 to 8 May 2026. Find attached the First Bulletin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DIS2026 is now the 33rd in an annual series of International Workshops. It
will cover a broad range of topics related to Quantum Chromodynamics and
Deep Inelastic Scattering, as well as the most exciting developments in
high-energy physics. A significant part of the programme is devoted to the
most recent theoretical advances and results from large experiments at BNL,
CERN, DESY, FNAL, JLab and KEK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The venue of the workshop is the Royal Hotel Carlton Conference Centre,
located in Bologna city centre. Participation will be in person only. The
DIS conference is back in Bologna after 25 years: the 9th edition was held
in Bologna in 2001.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientific programme will start on Monday morning and conclude on Friday
afternoon. It will feature plenary sessions with invited talks on Monday and
Friday, as well as six parallel sessions with contributed talks the other
days. Short “flash” talks will also be included in the parallel sessions,
providing visibility to the work of young scientists and fostering further
discussion during breaks. A preliminary version of the programme is already
available on the conference website, &lt;a class="link" href="https://dis2026.infn.it" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://dis2026.infn.it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in previous editions, the 2026 Guido Altarelli Award will be presented
during DIS2026. The Guido Altarelli Award honours the memory of the late
Guido Altarelli, one of the founding fathers of QCD, an outstanding
communicator of particle physics, and a mentor and strong supporter of Early
Career Scientists. The Guido Altarelli Award includes a certificate and a
monetary prize. It is awarded to young scientists for outstanding scientific
contributions to the fields covered by the DIS Conference series. Deadline
for nominations is 20th November 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Workshop proceedings will be published on Proceedings of Science. Daily
on-site lunches and coffee breaks, a welcome reception and a conference
dinner are included in the conference fee and will promote opportunities for
informal interaction and scientific exchange. The social excursion on
Thursday afternoon — a guided walking tour through Bologna’s historic centre
— will offer participants a chance to discover the city’s rich cultural and
architectural heritage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Workshop is jointly organised by the Bologna and Ferrara Divisions of
the Italian National Institute for Nuclear Physics (INFN), the Department of
Physics and Astronomy “Augusto Righi” of the University of Bologna, and the
Department of Physics and Earth Sciences of the University of Ferrara.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any questions, please contact the organizers at
&lt;a class="link" href="mailto:dis2026-info@lists.bo.infn.it" &gt;dis2026-info@lists.bo.infn.it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to welcoming you to Bologna.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the Local Organizing Committee,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pietro Antonioli
DIS2026 Chair
INFN Bologna&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bangkok Workshop on Gravity and Cosmology</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/bankgok-2026/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/bankgok-2026/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear colleagues,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the 3rd Bangkok Workshop on Gravity and
Cosmology, which will be held at Chulalongkorn University from February 2nd
to 6th, 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives:&lt;br&gt;
The workshop will cover a broad range of topics in gravity and theoretical
cosmology, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gravitational instabilities and collapse problems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Singularity resolution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canonical approaches to gravity quantization and quantum cosmology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistics of fluctuations in cosmological spacetimes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primordial black holes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cosmological dynamics of fundamental constants&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Format:&lt;br&gt;
To foster a collaborative environment, the talks will be informal and
interactive. We strongly encourage blackboard presentations to facilitate
discussions and clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registration details and further information is available on the workshop
website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3rd Bangkok Workshop on Gravity and Cosmology
&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.thaihep.phys.sc.chula.ac.th/BKK2026GRQC/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://www.thaihep.phys.sc.chula.ac.th/BKK2026GRQC/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We encourage you to save the date and share this announcement with
interested colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to seeing you in Bangkok&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best regards,&lt;br&gt;
Alfio Bonanno&lt;br&gt;
On behalf of the Scientific Organizing Committee (SOC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>QuanTO seminar (12th of September)</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/quanto-20250912/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/quanto-20250912/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear All,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the forthcoming event of the recently established lecture series &amp;ldquo;QuanTO - Quantum Lectures in Torino&amp;rdquo;. This joint initiative is the result of the scientific cooperation among researchers from the Departments of Physics and Mathematics of Politecnico di Torino (DISMA-DISAT) and Università di Torino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this series is to bring together physicists and mathematicians interested in quantum theories through regular meetings and advanced lectures on current topics by leading experts. We are particularly committed to engaging students and young researchers with these fascinating areas. Therefore, to encourage broader participation, each conference will be preceded by one or more introductory lectures (&amp;ldquo;crash course&amp;rdquo;) designed to review the ideas and techniques necessary to fully appreciate the advanced seminar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next event of this series will take place on September 12, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to host Professor Roberto Longo from the University of Rome Tor Vergata on this occasion, who will talk about&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;von Neumann algebras and entropy/energy inequalities in QFT&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event will take place at the Department of Mathematics &amp;ldquo;G. Peano&amp;rdquo; (UniTo), Aula Magna (2nd floor), with the following schedule - please find the event leaflet attached:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crash course from 10:30 to 12:30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seminar from 15:00 to 16:00.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract: After a brief introduction to operator algebras, I will present new inequalities concerning entropy and energy; in particular, my recent relative entropy/energy ratio local bound in Quantum Field Theory. This bound is model-independent and rigorous; it follows solely from first principles in the framework of translation-covariant, local Quantum Field Theory on the Minkowski spacetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A light lunch will be offered to the participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No registration is required. Should you have any inquiries, please feel free to contact us at &lt;a class="link" href="mailto:quanto.lectures@gmail.com" &gt;quanto.lectures@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;. Further information can be found on the webpage of the series: &lt;a class="link" href="https://sites.google.com/view/quantolectures" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://sites.google.com/view/quantolectures&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We kindly ask you to circulate this message to any potential participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Organizing Committee:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riccardo Adami, Laura Andrianopoli, Andrea Cavaglià, Dario Martelli, Marco Meineri, Fabrizio Nieri, S. Ivan Trapasso, Mario Trigiante&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Santo Stefano Belbo 2025</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/ssb-mail2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/ssb-mail2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Good news, everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Santo Stefano Belbo retreat is happening again in 2025!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you weren’t with us two years ago: every other year we organize a relaxed weekend workshop in Santo Stefano Belbo, a lovely spot not far from Torino. We spend two days together sharing our work, chatting about ideas, enjoying good food, great wine, and just having a nice time as a group (*), helping to spark new conversations and collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, we’ll be going on Saturday and Sunday, November 15–16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, just save the date and feel free to start signing up on our (still in progress) Indico page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/e/SSB25" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/e/SSB25&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please keep in mind that you will have to take care of your own accommodation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to another fun and inspiring weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrea, Antonio, Domenico &amp;amp; Marco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(*) (good) music included.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>First Circular - CRIS-MAC 2026 (Sorrento, 13 - 17 July, 2026)</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/crismac2026-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/crismac2026-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Please find the first circular for the XIV edition of the workshop CRIS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="CRISMAC-2026_-_FirstCircular.pdf" &gt;first circular&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Workshop “Perspectives at the Bellotti IBF” - Second Circular</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/bellotti-2025/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/bellotti-2025/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per incarico del Direttore si trasmette in allegato la Second Circular del
workshop dal titolo &amp;ldquo;Perspectives at the Bellotti IBF&amp;rdquo;, che si terrà dal
giorno 8 al giorno 10 ottobre 2025 presso la sala Maiorana dei LNGS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il link alla pagina web dedicata è il seguente:
(&lt;a class="link" href="https://ibf-workshop.sites.lngs.infn.it/%29" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://ibf-workshop.sites.lngs.infn.it/)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cordiali saluti&lt;br&gt;
Servizio Direzione LNGS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="Second_Circular___Perspectives_at_IBF_2025-1.pdf" &gt;second circular&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>WIFAI 2025</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/wifai-2025/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/wifai-2025/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Colleagues,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that the 4th Italian Workshop on the Physics at
High Intensity (WIFAI) will take place in Bari, Italy, from 11 to 14
November 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/event/43895/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/event/43895/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please save the date and feel free to share this announcement with
colleagues and collaborators who might be interested in attending (Deadline
for registration 8 Sept 2025).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop will feature a &amp;ldquo;Young Scientist Forum&amp;rdquo;, offering early-career
researchers in the high-intensity physics community an opportunity to
present their work and share innovative ideas (Deadline for abstract
submission 1 Sept 2025)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to welcoming you to Bari!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With best regards,&lt;br&gt;
Marco Pappagallo&lt;br&gt;
on behalf of the Local Organising Committee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Awarding of the Galileo Medal</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/galileo-2025/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/galileo-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On July 17, there will be a ceremony at the GGI for the awarding of the Galileo Medal to Pierre Sikivie e Leonard Susskind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please find the poster and the invitation with the program here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="invito_ggi_2025.jpg" &gt;invitation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a class="link" href="locandina_ggi_2025.pdf" &gt;program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From Puzzles to New Insights in Fundamental Physics</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/puzzles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/puzzles/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Conferenza &amp;ldquo;From Puzzles to New Insights in
Fundamental Physics&amp;rdquo;, Campagna (Salerno), 23-27 June 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per maggior informazioni, consultare il link: &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.pifp2025.it/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://www.pifp2025.it/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Workshop per Wanda</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/workshop-per-wanda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/workshop-per-wanda/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stiamo organizzando per il 3-4 luglio un piccolo workshop per celebrare i
75 anni di Wanda Alberico, andata purtroppo in pensione in periodo Covid.
Stiamo invitando suoi passati studenti e collaboratori ora in altri
istituti, incoraggiandoli anche a proporre dei talk sui comuni interessi e
progetti di ricerca.
Penso sarebbe bello che anche suoi vecchi colleghi e colleghe del
dipartimento e della sezione possano, se lo desiderano, partecipare.
Ti giro il link per iscriversi (per noi utile per organizzare la logistica
in base al numero di partecipanti), pregando di farlo circolare tra il
personale di gruppo 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/event/46508/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/event/46508/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cari saluti&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrea Beraudo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025 Workshop on Resummation, Evolution, Factorization</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/ref2025/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/ref2025/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Dear colleague,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the forthcoming 12th edition of the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workshop on Resummation, Evolution, Factorization (REF 2025)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://agenda.infn.it/event/43981/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://agenda.infn.it/event/43981/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop will be held at the Department of Physics of the
University of Milan from October 13 to October 17, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registration and call for abstracts are open from the Indico webpage above. All
relevant details can be found there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We encourage you to circulate this announcement among colleagues who might
be interested in the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to see you in Milan!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best regards,
Giancarlo Ferrera and Lorenzo Rossi (for the LOC)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>