<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IT on Group IV News</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/tags/it/</link><description>Recent content in IT on Group IV News</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/tags/it/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Yearly IP cleanup</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/ip-cleanup-2025/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/ip-cleanup-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are doing our yearly cleanup of the unused IP addresses.&lt;br&gt;
We have a finite number of IPs &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; by law each of them must be uniquely attributed to a precise person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since mistakes can always happen, if your LAN-connected computer (desktop) stops being able to access the internet, please contact me or our &lt;a class="link" href="mailto:central-support@to.infn.it" &gt;central-support@to.infn.it&lt;/a&gt; immediately (yes, I do see the catch-22 situation, but I&amp;rsquo;m positive you can find a way).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>🪦 R.I.P. zoroastro (624 BC–2025) – Long Live artaban! 🎉</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/rip-zoroastro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/rip-zoroastro/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Dear all,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is with a heavy heart (and a slightly overheated CPU) that we announce the passing of zoroastro, our loyal SSH server and steadfast companion through login storms, accidental rm -rf, and infinite loops since time immemorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After years of noble service—during which zoroastro survived kernel panics, mysterious downtime, and that one time someone tried to mine bitcoins (I&amp;rsquo;m not joking), our venerable server has finally ascended to the great /dev/null in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But fear not! From the ashes of zoroastro rises a worthy successor: artaban is now ready to serve all your SSH-ing needs with dignity and RAM to spare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effective immediately, please direct your logins, scripts, and affection to:&lt;br&gt;
👉 artaban.to.infn.it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the home directory contents are still there and aliases should redirect smoothly. But do check your scripts and cron jobs just in case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rest in peace, dear zoroastro you were the SSH server we didn’t deserve but desperately needed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>UPS</title><link>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/ups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://domenicoo.github.io/gr4-news/p/ups/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are planning to buy a few UPS (uninterruptible power supplies) to change our aging ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send me a mail if you need one for your office (and please tell people around because some of my emails end up straight to the spam).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Welcome to Hugo theme Stack. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing! --&gt;
&lt;!-- For more information about this theme, check the documentation: https://stack.jimmycai.com/ --&gt;
&lt;!-- Want a site like this? Check out [hugo-theme-stack-stater](https://github.com/CaiJimmy/hugo-theme-stack-starter) --&gt;
&lt;!-- &gt; Photo by [Pawel Czerwinski](https://unsplash.com/@pawel_czerwinski) on [Unsplash](https://unsplash.com/) --&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>